Gaurav Manchanda

Technical Lead - Gurgaon | Remote

\(+91 99995 95554

@ gauravmanchanda16@gmail.com

in https://linkedin.com/in/gauravmanchanda16

• https://github.com/gauravmanchanda

Summary

A Polyglot Web Developer with more than 10 years of experience working across domains & with numerous technologies. Have mostly been into Ruby on Rails and have worked with it for around 7 years, plus some stints with Python, Golang.

Enthusiastic about Elixir & Crystal. Have contributed to an Open Source project called Coherence https://github.com/smpallen99/coherence,

which is a Authentication system like Devise built for Phoenix, which is a Ruby on Rails inspired framework for Elixir

Skills

Operating Systems: Linux, MacOS, Windows

Languages: Ruby, Golang, Python some Crystal & Elixir

Web Frameworks: Ruby on Rails, Gin, Echo, Roda, Hug, a little Phoenix

Web Servers: NGINX, Apache

Databases: PostgreSQL, MySQL, Redis, Memcached **Project Management Tools**: JIRA, Pivotal Tracker

VCS: Git

CI/CD: CircleCI, Codeship, Gitlab

Container Orchestration: Docker, Kubernetes, Minikube

Work Experience

Builder.Al

Technical Lead March 2019 - Present

Working Hands On as a Technical Lead, handling a team of around 15 people distributed across London, Ukraine & India. Working on an Cloud Aggregator Billing & Reports app, ingesting hundreds of Gigs of data daily to enable customers to visualize their usage patterns.

Ruby, Rails, Sidekiq, PostgreSQL, Javascript, Gitlab, AWS Redshift etc.

Upgraded Technologies (Y Combinator Accelerator)

Senior Software Engineer - Remote

January 2018 - March 2019

Working on the product enabling users to upgrade their Electronic devices every year. Worked on the 'Pay via Upgraded' solution to enable Third party services to use Upgraded as a payment method. Coding, reviewing code & mentoring people. Also working as a Project Manager, handling Story Creation, Sprints etc

Ruby, Rails, Redis, Sidekiq, ElasticSearch, PostgreSQL, Docker, Docker Compose, Javascript, CircleCI, Git etc.

Xebia IT Architects

Senior Consultant

April 2016 - January 2018

Worked on multiple projects ranging from Wealth Management, multiple Internal Organization Tools to a major task of Dockerizing 15-20 Application created in Rails/NodeJS/Angular/React etc and take them to the cloud.

Ruby, Rails, NodeJS, Oracle, MySQL, Redis, MongoDB, PostgreSQL, Docker, Docker Compose, Javascript, CircleCI, Git etc.

ThoughtWorks Technologies

Consultant

June 2014 - March 2016

Worked on multiple projects ranging from Aviation to Betting domains, a Survey app like SurveyMonkey, majorly with Ruby on Rails. Played the role of a Senior Developer, a Mentor & a Team Lead as well. Worked in teams ranging from 5 to 60 people.

Ruby, Rails, MySQL, Redis, PostgreSQL, Vagrant, Chef, GoCD, Git, JIRA, CoffeeScript, JavaScript, RSpec, Cucumber, Resque etc.

Vinsol

Team Lead

November 2011 - June 2014

Worked on eCommerce projects, mostly on 1 eCommerce product based out of Nigeria.

Worked on it for more than 2 years. Started as 1 of the 2 devs in the team to leading a team of 15 people for the same project. Started as a Single Server app, which eveolved to a distributed app to run on more than 8 servers.

Worked on Optimizing the app, minimizing the response time, optimizing SQL queries, images, css, the Ruby code etc.

Ruby, Rails, MySQL, DelayedJob, Codeship, Git, JIRA, BaseCamp, JavaScript, RSpec, jQuery, Prototype etc

Webchutney Studios

Software Engineer

June 2011 - November 2011

Majorly worked on Drupal Websites for Canon, Fortis Hospitals etc

PHP, Perl, MySQL, Javascript, jQuery

eNuke Software

Senior Engneer

January 2011 - June 2011

Majorly worked on some Drupal Websites

PHP, Perl, MySQL, Smarty Templates, Javascript, jQuery

TeeSort

Web Architect & Developer

April 2010 - January 2011

Worked on Teesort.com, a crowdsourcing T-Shirt Website, where users would submit designs, be voted and chosen to be printed

PHP, MySQL, OpenCart, Javascript, jQuery.

Successive Softwares

Junior Developer

June 2009 - March 2010

Started with working on Web Crawlers, crawled data for multiple Real Estate sites. Worked on a site created on PHP to display the collected data, based out of Denmark.

Python, PHP, MySQL, Javascript.

Education

Kurukshetra University

Bachelor of Technology

September 2005 - June 2009